<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Java on Jian Liew</title><link>https://jianliew.me/blog/tags/java/</link><description>Recent content in Java on Jian Liew</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jianliew.me/blog/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Singleton &amp; Observer Pattern (Java)</title><link>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/november-2019/singletonobserverpattern/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/november-2019/singletonobserverpattern/</guid><description>This blog post will demonstrate a simple use case where the singleton and observable design pattern becomes important.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine if you are in the arcade and there is a Lucky Dip Machine. The reason I like call it the LuckyDipMachine is because it is one of the feature assignments in the Programming Foundation Units in Monash University and it is often times made fun at. However, the solution for assignment itself can be engineered to be better.</description></item><item><title>Min and Max value of an Array (Java)</title><link>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/november-2019/minmax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/november-2019/minmax/</guid><description>There are many ways to obtain the min and maximum value of items inside of an Array. This blog post will show case its many ways.
The most basic way to do this is to loop through the entire array manually. The benefit of doing it this way, is that it just relies on the standard library and can be easily rewritten to an even simpler form. This way uses the Math.</description></item><item><title>Programming to an Interface (Java)</title><link>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/november-2019/programmingtoaninterface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/november-2019/programmingtoaninterface/</guid><description>A question that often arises is, what is the benefit of programming to an interface? This blog post will attempt to explain why. It is quite common for people to have heard of the term but do not really understand the significance of it.
The most commonly used example is as follows. Notice that in this example, the LHS (Left hand side), is using List while the RHS (Right hand side) is specifying it to be ArrayList.</description></item></channel></rss>