<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reddit on Jian Liew</title>
    <link>https://jianliew.me/blog/tags/reddit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reddit on Jian Liew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 20:56:02 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jianliew.me/blog/tags/reddit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Chart</title>
      <link>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/october-2019/percentage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 20:56:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/october-2019/percentage/</guid>
      <description>The charts here are visualisation of the AmIthea-hole subreddit which can be found here
The reason this post is made, is so that it would easier to see the percentage of votes of a certain type.
Please note that the posts here are generated based on the Reddit website by doing GET requests. So, it is based on their current entries.
    Abbreviation Meaning     YTA You&amp;rsquo;re the A-hole   NTA Not the A-hole   ESH Everyone sucks here   NAH No A-holes here   INFO Not Enough Info    Posts   let summary = []; let parseResult = (link) = { const endPoint = &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Word Cloud </title>
      <link>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/october-2019/programmming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 20:56:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/october-2019/programmming/</guid>
      <description>The word cloud generated here is based on the **/r/programming** subreddit for reddit.com The reason this post is made, is so that it would easier to see the word that appeared the most for the day. Even though the use of a word cloud is not exactly a good representation of occurrence, it still looks nice. Please note that the posts here are generated based on the Reddit website by doing GET requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/october-2019/hk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 20:56:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jianliew.me/blog/blog/october-2019/hk/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Analysis for the Sub-Reddit &amp;ldquo;HongKong&amp;rdquo; This post will perform sentiment analysis using AFINN. AFINN is a list of words rated for valence rated with an integer between minus five(negative) and plus five (positive). This implementation uses AFINN-en-165. 1
This approach however is a very naive approach as it does not build any models to determine the context of the usage of the word itself.
Please note that the posts here are generated based on the Reddit website by doing GET requests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>